Guide to the Naval History Society Records 1907-1943 (bulk 1909-1936) MS 439.53
@ 2011 New-York Historical Society
Naval History Society Records
1907-1943 (bulk 1909-1936)
MS 439.53
@ 2011 New-York Historical Society
17.3 Linear feet (33 boxes, 17 volumes)
The collection includes records of the Society's financial, membership, library, and manuscript collecting and publishing activities, as well as general correspondence.
Provenance
Donated to the New-York Historical Society by the Naval History Society in 1925.
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers.
Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to twenty exposures of stable, unbound material per day. (Researchers may not accrue unused copy amounts from previous days.)[ Researchers on site may print out unlimited copies from microfilm reader-printer machines at per-exposure rates. See guidelines in Reading room for details.]
Historical Note
According to the 1915 catalog of the library of Naval History Society founder John Sanford Barnes (see Series 3), "The Naval History Society has been established for the purpose of publishing and preserving manuscripts, documents, and writings relating to our naval history, naval art and science, and the surroundings and experiences of seamen in general and of American seamen in particular."
The Naval History Society Collection began with the donation to the Society in 1915 of Barnes's personal collections by his son, Col. James Barnes (see Series 4). The donation included library materials now cataloged in the XN classification in the New-York Historical Society Library, artifacts now included in the New-York Historical Society's museum collections, as well as the manuscript materials described in Series 1-52 of this Collection. The entire collection was donated to the New-York Historical Society, where the Naval History Society collections and office were then located, in 1925. Additional materials were donated by Naval History Society members and others or acquired by purchase after that date, some from the Naval History Fund established at the New-York Historical Society from the Naval History Society's monies.
A chronology of the Society's publishing activities is provided in Subseries VI. Manuscript collections and Society publication records.
Chronology of the Naval History Society
1909 Meeting convenes at the New York Yacht Club to discuss formation of a naval history society. Attendees include Admiral Caspar Goodrich (see Series 21), William Conant Church (biographer of John Ericsson [Series 16]), Col. James Barnes (see Series 4), and Franklin D. Roosevelt, who serves as the meeting's secretary. John Sanford Barnes is unanimously elected president and Robert Neeser secretary-treasurer. A committee is authorized to inquire if the New-York Historical Society would serve as the Naval History Society's home.
1911 John Sanford Barnes dies.
1912 Naval History Society incorporated. Its offices are located at 247 Fifth Avenue, although some early meetings are held in Washington, DC.
1915 James Barnes donates the collections of his father John Sanford Barnes to the Naval History Society in June. They include original manuscripts, letters, and logbooks as well as published books, pamphlets, and prints (approximately 3,570 volumes and separate items). The Society rents space in Aeolian Hall on West 42nd Street to house the collection.
1915 Secretary Robert Neeser corresponds with New-York Historical Society President John Abeel Weekes in May to ask if the Historical Society is interested in acquiring the Naval History Society collections and providing a room where it can be preserved for research and exhibition. Naval History Society, "being primarily a publication society...has...no habitat or place where these priceless and unique books could be preserved."
1915 New-York Historical Society Executive Committee responds to Neeser's request: "Owing to the crowded condition of the present building, the Captain Barnes collection was respectfully declined as a deposit."
1915 The John S. Barnes Memorial Library is transferred to the Naval History Society in September.
1916 John S. Barnes Memorial Library of the Naval History Society opens January 10 in Aeolian Hall. Marie Bayless serves as librarian.
1916 The Society holds an exhibition of the Library's books, prints, and manuscripts of John Paul Jones [see Series 28] in April, and in May of its Gustavus Conyngham memorabilia [see Series 10).
1917 The Society holds an exhibition of its Revolutionary War books, prints, and manuscripts in March, and in April on the War of 1812.
1918 Col. James Barnes elected President, a position he holds until his death in 1936.
1920 Alice M. Kyte becomes librarian.
1923 Franklin D. Roosevelt is deputized by the Building Committee to contact New-York Historical Society about collaborating on space and collections.
1925 Naval History Society relocates to New-York Historical Society, which was expanding its storage and exhibition spaces, and its members automatically become Associate members of New-York Historical Society. The $15,000 Naval History Fund is also transferred, to be used to purchase additional materials for the collection.
1930 Naval History Society participates in the restoration of gravestone for William Paul (brother of John Paul Jones; see Series 28), in St. George's Churchyard, Fredericksburg, VA.
1932 Naval History Society materials are represented in New-York Historical Society's "Ships and Steamboats" exhibition.
1936 Collection of dues and publication activities are suspended following the death of Col. James Barnes and insufficient Naval History Fund monies to purchase additional materials.
Scope and Content Note
The collection consists of the Naval History Society's organizational and financial records (including account books, checks, and receipts). They document the establishment and administration of the Society from its foundation until it ceased independent operations: its formation, officers and bylaws, membership, finances, library and manuscript collecting activities, and its editing and publication of volumes based on materials in its manuscript collections. It shows the context of naval and maritime collecting by the Society through its officers' correspondence with members and other collectors, authors, historical societies and repositories, and the Office of Naval Records, Washington, DC; as well as the organization's internal governance and workings.
Arrangement
The Naval History Society Records form Series 53 of the Naval History Society Collection, comprising 53 individual collections named for famous naval figures and ships, as well as the records of the Naval History Society itself, and donated to the New-York Historical Society by the Naval History Society in 1925.
The collection is arranged in seven series. Within each series materials are in chronological order unless otherwise noted; original order within folders has been retained.
Series I. Administrative records
Series II. Correspondence
Series III. Membership records
Series IV. Library records
Series V. Financial records
Series VI. Manuscript collections and Society publication records
Series VII. Ephemera
Related Material at The New-York Historical Society
The library collections of the Naval History Society were also donated to the New-York Historical Society in 1925 and are cataloged under the XN call number. Some artifacts were donated and are now in the Museum's collections.
Barck, Dorothy C.; Barnes, James, 1866-1936; Barnes, John S. (John Sanford), 1836-1911; Davis, C. (Charles Henry), 1845-1921; De Vinne Press; Kane, Grenville, 1854-1943; Naval History Society. John S. Barnes Memorial Library; Neeser, Robert Wilden b. 1884; New-York Historical Society. Library; New-York Historical Society; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945; Satterlee, Herbert Livingston, 1863-1947; Account books; Accounts; Bookplates; Catalogs; Certificates; Checkbooks; Checks; Clippings; Collectors and collecting --History; Correspondence; Drawings; Financial records; Historiography; History publishing - New York (State) - New York; Invitations; Invoices; Leases; Legal documents; Library catalogs; Manuscripts; Materials for history; Minutes; Naval history - catalogs and collections; Naval history - sources; New York (N.Y) - Societies, etc.; New York (N.Y.) - Societies, etc.; Notes; Publishers and publishing -- New York; Publishers' advertisements; Receipts; Reports; Seals; Stationery; Subscription lists; United States. Navy -- History - Sources; Vouchers
- Series I: Administrative Records (1909-1938)
  Scope and Contents note
  The subseries includes records of the founding and administration of the Society, its various locations, and officers. The President's reports (1928-1935, by Col. James Barnes) provide details of manuscript acquisitions and provenance, and the Society's publications for each year. The Secretary's reports (1926-1929, 1931-1935) focus on membership news: new members gained and those lost through death or resignation. The Treasurer's reports (1925-1936 by Robert Neeser) include information on the Naval History Fund, which was used to purchase additional library and manuscript materials.
  The original certificate of incorporation is signed by Franklin D. Roosevelt, before he became Assistant Secretary of the Navy, in his position at the Society's Secretary. The 1923-1924 Annual reports include James Barnes's own annotated copy. This edition includes a complete history of the Society to date: founders, minutes of annual meeting, resolutions, details on the collections and publications, and information on memorial activities in 1924 honoring Rear Admiral Thayer Mahan.
  Arrangement
  Printed letters sent to all members were moved to Subseries II. Correspondence, and arranged there chronologically.
  - Bylaws, proposed bylaws, certificate of incorporation, 1909-1910, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - History of the bill to incorporate the NHS, 1912 May 1-Aug 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - H.R. 24026: A Bill to Incorporate the Naval History Society, 1912 May 7 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Lists of officers, 1911, 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Drawing and camera-ready art for Naval History Society seal, [1912] (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Annual reports, 1911, 1913, 1914, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Annual reports, 1919, 1922, 1923-1924 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - President's reports, 1928-1935 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Secretary's reports, 1926-1929, 1931-1935 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Treasurer's reports, 1917-1922 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Treasurer's reports, 1925-1936 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Meeting minutes, 1909 May 8 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Meeting minutes and notices: Board of Managers, annual meetings, 1912-1919 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Meeting minutes and Treasurer's reports, 1920-1924 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Meeting minutes: annual meetings, Executive Committee, 1926-1926, 1930, 1931, 1933, 1935, 1936, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Leaflets about the Society, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Embosser, undated (Box 2)
  - Seals, undated (Box 3)
  - Minutes, 1909-1916 (Volume 1)
- Series II: Correspondence (1909-1943)
  The Society's correspondence includes incoming and carbon copies of outgoing letters, primarily to and from Secretary Robert Neeser and librarians Alice Kyte (Naval History Society) and Dorothy Barck (New-York Historical Society). Also represented are Col. James Barnes when he was active as President of the Society, Treasurer Grenville Kane, and attorney Herbert Satterlee. The correspondence documents all aspects of the Society's functions, including membership dues notices, publication of Naval History Society editions by The DeVinne Press and others, cataloging of Naval History Society publications by the Library of Congress, payment for or receipt of publications by members, research requests, and payment and other banking transactions. Contact with the New-York Historical Society begins in 1915 with formation of a Building Committee and discussion of a possible move of the collections from rented space in Aeolian Hall to the Historical Society's location, culminating in the move in 1925. Among that correspondence is a letter signed by Franklin Roosevelt. A November, 1936, letter to the membership announces the end of the publication program due to insufficient monies in the Naval History Fund.
  Most of the correspondence was originally bundled in multiple envelopes for each year, usually organized alphabetically by last name of correspondent. Exceptions included envelopes for 1909, which were arranged chronologically in one envelope; 1917, which began as an alphabetical run but sometimes included correspondence dating to 1923; 1920, which was bundled together with 1924; and various years for which there was only one envelope containing all correspondence, especially later in the Society's history. Some large runs of correspondence to one recipient or on a particular subject were labeled as such and stored together. Those divisions have been retained, but folders have been arranged in chronological order.
  - Correspondence, 1909 February - June (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1909 July - October (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1909 November - December (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence A, 1910 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence B, 1910 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence C, 1910 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence D, 1910 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence F, 1910 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence G, 1910 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence H, 1910 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence J-L, 1910 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence M, 1910 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence N, 1910 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence P-R, 1910 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence S, 1910 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence T-W, 1910 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence A-C, 1911 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence D-G, 1911 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence H-M, 1911 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence N, O, 1911 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence P, Q, 1911 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence R, S, 1911 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence T-Z, 1911 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence Misc., 1911 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence A,B, 1912 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence C, D, 1912 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence E-G, 1912 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence H-J, 1912 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence K-M, 1912 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence N, O, 1912 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence P-R, 1912 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence S, 1912 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence T-Z, 1912 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Invitation to join Naval History Society, [1912] (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence A-D, 1913 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence E-G, 1913 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence H, 1913 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence I-K, 1913 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence L, 1913 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence M, 1913 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence N-O, 1913 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence P-Q, 1913 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence R, 1913 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence S, 1913 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence T-Z, 1913 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence A, B, 1914 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence C, D, 1914 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence E, F, 1914 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence G, 1914 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence H, 1914 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence I, J, 1914 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence K, L, 1914 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence M, 1914 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence N, O, 1914 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence P, Q, 1914 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence R, 1914 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence S, 1914 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence T-Z, 1914 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence A, 1915 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence B, 1915 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence C, 1915 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence D, E 1, 915 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence F, 1915 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence G, 1915 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence H, 1915 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence I, J, 1915 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence K, 1915 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence L, 1915 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence M, 1915 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence N-Q, 1915 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence R, 1915 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence S, 1915 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence T, 1915 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence U-Y, 1915 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence A, B, 1916 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence C, 1916 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence D, 1916 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence E, 1916 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence F, 1916 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence G, 1916 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence H, 1916 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence I-K, 1916 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence L, 1916 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence M, 1916 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence N, O, 1916 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence P, 1916 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence Q, R, 1916 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence S, 1916 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence T-Z, 1916 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence about John Paul Jones, 1916-1931 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence A,B, 1917 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence C-G, 1917 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence H, 1917 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence I-K, 1917 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence Grenville Kane, 1917 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence L, 1917 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence Library Rent Fund, Library Fund, 1917 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence M, 1917-1923 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence N, 1917 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence O-Q, 1917 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence R, 1917 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence S, 1917 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence T, 1917 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence X-Z, 1917 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence A, B, 1918 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence C, D, 1918 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence E, F, 1918 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence G, 1918 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence H, 1918 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence I-K, 1918 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence Grenville Kane, 1918 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence L, M, 1918 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence N, O, 1918 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence P, Q, 1918 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence R, 1918 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence S, 1918 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence T-Z, 1918 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence A, B, 1919 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence C, D, 1919 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence E, F, 1919 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence G, H, 1919 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence I-K, 1919 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence Grenville Kane, 1919 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence L, 1919 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence M, 1919 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence N, O, 1919 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence P-R, 1919 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence S, 1919 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence T, 1919 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence U-Z, 1919 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence A, 1920 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence B, 1920 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence C, 1920 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence D, 1920 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence E, F, 1920 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence G, 1920 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence H-J, 1920 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence K, 1920 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence L, 1920 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Library rent fund, 1920 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence N, 1920 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence O, P, 1920 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence Q, R, 1920 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence S, 1920 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence T, 1920 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence U, V, 1920 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence W, Z, 1920 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Orders for Vol I Fox papers, 1920 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Acknowledgments Vol I Fox papers, 1920 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence to Board of Directors, 1920 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Acknowledgments Vol II Fox papers, 1921 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence A-D, 1921 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence E-H, 1921 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence K-R, 1921 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence S-T, 1921 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence U-Y, 1921 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Acknowledgments Garnerey's print of Constitution and Guerriere, 1921 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Resignations, 1922-1923 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence A-D, 1922 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence Barnes, 1922, undated (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence E-H, 1922 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence K-R, 1922 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence S-T, 1922 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence U-Z, 1922 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence A, 1923 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Replies to annual meeting notice, 1923 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1924 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence B, 1924 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence C, 1924 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence D, 1924 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence E, F, 1924 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence G, 1924 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence H-J, 1924 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence K, 1924 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence L, 1924 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence M, 1924 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence N, 1924 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence O, P, 1924 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence Q, R, 1924 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence S, 1924 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence T, 1924 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence U, V, 1924 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence W-Z, 1924 (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Isaac Hull manuscript donation: Correspondence with executors of Charles Allen Munn, 1924 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, including to Col. Barnes, 1925 (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Letter to Barnes from New-York Historical Society, 1925 May 20 (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - Letter to members about New-York Historical Society move, 1925 June 25 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Letter to members about associate membership in New-York Historical Society, 1925 October 21 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Letters from members accepting associate membership in New-York Historical Society, 1925 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Resignations and deaths, 1925 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, including to and from Col. Barnes, 1926 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1926 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1927 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, Col. Barnes, 1927 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1928 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, Col. Barnes, 1928 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1929 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1930 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, Barnes-Barck, 1930-1932 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Barnes-Andrews correspondence about frigate Constitution, 1930-1934 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence Barnes, 1930-1936 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Annual meeting notices; notification of Garnerey print, 1930-1933, undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1931 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Acknowledgments "Rope Yarns", 1931 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Orders: "Rope Yarns", 1931-1932 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1932 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Acknowledgments "Life of Wm. Bainbridge", 1932 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Acknowledgments Rodney books, 1932 Oct-Dec (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Resignations, 1932 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1933 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1933 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Barnes-Gurn correspondence about John Barry, 1933-1934 (Box 18, Folder 12)